SolutionsProductsPricingResourcesWhat's New[Contact Us](https://matterport.com/contact-us)[Sign In](https://authn.matterport.com/auth/login)[Start Free](https://buy.matterport.com/free-account-register)

Sales: [+1(888) 993-8990](tel:+1(888) 993-8990)

EN

Privacy Policy
==============

Last updated: November 15, 2024

Introduction
------------

This privacy notice (“Privacy Policy”) describes how Matterport, Inc.’s (“Company,” “we,” “us”, or “our”) collects information about you (“you”, “your”), in compliance with GDPR, CCPA, CPRA, VCDPA, and other relevant data privacy laws, through your interactions with our products, services, mobile and desktop applications (the “Applications”) and websites, including [www.matterport.com](https://matterport.com/), (the “Website”) (collectively, the “Services”).

Please read this Privacy Policy carefully to understand our views and practices regarding your personal information and how we will treat it. By using any of the Services, you confirm you have agreed to the Terms of Use and read and understood this Privacy Policy and our [Cookie Policy](https://matterport.com/cookie-policy). For more information about Data Privacy within Showcase, [click here](https://matterport.com/showcase-data-privacy).

We take the privacy of users very seriously, and we will not share personal information of users in way unrelated to those described in this Privacy Policy.

What information we collect, and why
------------------------------------

We collect various information regarding you or your device you use to access the Services. The following provides examples of the type of information that we collect from you and how we use that information. In accordance with CPRA and VCDPA, we recognize your right to correct inaccurate personal information, limit the use and disclosure of sensitive personal information, and opt out of the sale of personal information, as described more fully below.

|     |     |     |
| --- | --- | --- |
| **Context** | **Types of Data** | **Primary Purpose for Collection and Use of Data** |
| User Information | When you register for a Matterport account we collect your full name, email address, and account log-in credentials. | We have a legitimate interest in contacting our Users and communicating with them concerning normal business administration such as projects, services, and billing. |
| User Account information | We may collect personal information, such as your name, phone number, address, company, and e-mail address when you register for our Services, purchase products, sign up for our mailing lists, or otherwise communicate with us. | We have a legitimate interest in contacting our Users and communicating with them concerning normal business administration such as projects, services, and billing. |
| Cookies and first party tracking | We use cookies and clear GIFs. “Cookies” are small pieces of information that a website sends to a computer’s hard drive while a web site is viewed. See our [Cookie Policy](https://matterport.com/cookie-policy) for more information. | We have a legitimate interest in making our Website operate efficiently. |
| Cookies and Third-Party Tracking | We participate in behavior-based advertising, this means that a third party uses technology (e.g., a cookie) to collect information about your use of our Website so that they can provide advertising about products and services tailored to your interests on our Website, or on other websites. | We have a legitimate interest in engaging in behavior-based advertising and capturing website analytics. |
| Demographic Information | We collect personal information, such as your age or location. | We have a legitimate interest in understanding our customers and providing tailored services. |
| Distance Information | When you use a Matterport camera in conjunction with our mobile applications, to better provide the Services we collect your current location information provided from the camera or mobile devices built-in GPS sensors, and from information derived from cell tower triangulation. We may use your IP address information to determine your approximate location. The mobile device OS will always prompt you for permission to use location data and we do not bypass this OS provided permission functionality in our mobile applications. We also use location data to assist the processing of image data and to better understand how multiple scan locations are related to each other. | We have a legitimate interest in understanding our customers and providing tailored services. In some contexts, our use is also based upon your consent to provide us with geo location information. We also have a legitimate interest in providing aggregated analytics to better understand how and where the Service is being used, to provide a customized and localized experience when using the Service, and to prevent access to the Services where required by law. |
| Email Interconnectivity | If you receive email from us, we use certain tools to capture data related to when you open our message, click on any links or banners it contains and make purchases. | We have a legitimate interest in understanding how you interact with our communications to you. |
| Employment | If you apply for a job posting, or become an employee, we collect information necessary to process your application or to retain you as an employee. This may include, among other things, your Social Security Number. Providing this information is required for employment. | We use information about current employees to perform our contract of employment, or the anticipation of a contract of employment with you. In some contexts, we are also required by law to collect information about our employees. We also have a legitimate interest in using your information to have efficient staffing and work force operations. |
| Feedback/Support | We collect personal information from you contained in any inquiry you submit to us regarding our Website or Services, such as completing our online forms, calling, or emailing for the purposes of general inquiries, support requests, or to report an issue. We may ask for your first and last name, physical address, email address, phone number, company name, industry type, details about your current product usage, and certain other information from time to time. When you communicate with us over the phone, your calls may be recorded and analyzed for training, quality control and for sales and marketing purposes and we will collect the phone number you use to call Matterport, as well as other information you may provide during the call. During such calls we will notify you of the recording via either voice prompt or script. If you provide your phone number, we may use that information to make direct dial calls, autodialed and prerecorded message calls, and to send text messages, from Matterport relating to our products and services. | We have a legitimate interest in receiving, and acting upon, your feedback, issues, or inquiries. |
| Images stored and processed | When you capture images using a Matterport camera or other devices, or if you provide images from any other source and upload them to the Matterport Platform (as described in the Platform Subscription Agreement), we may collect personal information which is depicted within the imagery you submit. | We have a legitimate interest in collecting customer images to provide the Services. |
| Mailing List | When you sign up for one of our mailing lists we collect your email address or postal address. | We share information about our Services with individuals that consent to receive such information. We also have a legitimate interest in sharing information about our products or services. |
| Mobile Application Logs | We collect information related to your use of our Capture App, including details about how you interact with the app, such as feature usage, button clicks, and navigation paths. Additionally, we gather data about the device you use, including the device model, operating system, and unique device identifiers. With your consent, we may also collect geolocation data to enhance app functionality and provide location-based services. | We have a legitimate interest in monitoring the usage and performance of our Capture App. Among other things, this helps us understand which features and functionalities within the app are most popular, how users interact with the app, and how we can improve the overall user experience. |
| Mobile Devices | When you download or use apps relating to our Website, we may collect information about your location and your mobile device, including a unique identifier for your device. Most mobile devices allow you to turn off location services. If you have questions about how to disable your device’s location services, we recommend you contact your mobile service carrier or your device manufacturer. | We have a legitimate interest in connection with our efforts to prevent fraud or illicit use of our Processing Services and to provide you with location-based services, such as advertising, search results, and other personalized content. |
| Order Placement | We collect your name, billing address, e-mail address, phone number, and credit card number when you place an order. | We use your information to perform our contract to provide you with products or services. |
| Payment and transaction information | We collect information such as the model of a camera purchased, subscription plans purchased, date and time of your transaction, and payment information, such as your credit card or bank account details. | We have a legitimate interest in facilitating transactions, detecting and preventing fraud and keeping a record of your purchases so we can provide you Customer Support and warranty services, and for financial purposes as required by law. We do not process your credit card information directly, but rather this information is processed by one or more 3rd-party payment processors. |
| Promotions | Promotions, incentives or giveaways may be made available through Matterport, our Partners, or third parties from time to time. You do not have to participate in these. However, if you choose to participate, you may be asked to disclose some personal information. Additionally, at the time of entering the promotion, we will disclose in the promotion’s materials specific terms and conditions regarding how your personal information will be used. Please do not participate in any promotion if you do not agree to such usage. | We have a legitimate interest in sharing information about our Services and providing incentives to our customers. |
| Surveys | When you participate in a survey we collect information that you provide through the survey such as your email address, name and any other information you choose to include in the body of your email or responses. If the survey is provided by a third party service provider, the third party’s privacy policy applies to the collection, use, and disclosure of your information. | We have a legitimate interest in understanding your opinions, and collecting information relevant to our organization. |
| Website interactions | We use technology to monitor how you interact with our Website. This may include which links you click on, the URL that you visited before you came to our Services, the URL to which you next go to, information about the browser through which you are accessing the Services, and your Internet Protocol (IP) address or information that you type into our online forms. This may also include information about your device or browser. | We have a legitimate interest in understanding how you interact with our Website to better improve it, and to understand your preferences and interests in order to select offerings that you might find most useful. We also have a legitimate interest in detecting and preventing fraud. |
| Web logs | We collect information, including your browser type, operating system, Internet Protocol (IP) address (a number that is automatically assigned to a computer when the Internet is used), domain name, click-activity, referring website, and/or a date/time stamp for visitors. | We have a legitimate interest in monitoring our networks and the visitors to our Website. Among other things, it helps us understand which of our Services is the most popular. |

How we use your personal information
------------------------------------

In addition to the purposes and uses described above, we use information in the following ways:

* _**Provision of the Services.**_ To create and manage your account, provide, and personalize our Services, process payments, and respond to your inquiries.
    
* _**Communicating with you**_. To communicate with you, including by sending you emails about your transactions and Service-related announcements.
    
* _**Promotion.**_ To promote our Services and send you tailored marketing communications about products, services, offers, programs, and promotions of Matterport and our partners and measure the success of those campaigns. For example, we may send different marketing communications to you based on your subscription plan or what we think may interest you based on other information we hold about you.
    
* _**Advertising.**_ To analyze your interactions with our Services and third parties’ online services so we can tailor our advertising to what we think will interest you. For example, we may decide not to advertise our Services to you on a social media site if you already signed up for paid Services or we may choose to serve you a particular advertisement based on your subscription plan or what we think may interest you based on other information we hold about you.
    
* _**Direct marketing.**_ To contact you with information about our products and services. Most marketing messages we send will be by email and we may use personal information we collect about you to help us determine the most relevant marketing information to share with you. If you receive marketing email from us, you may unsubscribe at any time by following the instructions contained within the email. You can also view and modify settings relating to the nature and frequency of marketing communications that you receive from us as part of your user settings by logging into your account and changing your preferences. If you opt-out of receiving marketing email from us, it may take up to ten business days for us to process your opt-out request, and you may receive marketing email from us during that period. Additionally, even after you opt-out from receiving marketing messages from us, you will continue to receive administrative and transactional messages from us regarding your use of the Service.
    
* _**Customizing the Services.**_ To provide you with customized services. For example, we use your location information to determine your language preferences or display accurate date and time information.
    
* **_Improving and Monitoring our Services._** To analyze and learn about how the Services are accessed and used, evaluate, and improve our Services (including by developing new products and services and managing our communications) and monitor and measure the effectiveness of our advertising. We usually do this based on anonymous, pseudonymized or aggregated information which does not focus on you individually. We may use automated decision-making and profiling to tailor our services and communications.  We train our AI models using aggregated and anonymized data to help us refine our services and develop new features. For example, we use AI to enhance Matterport Spaces.
    
* _**Security.**_ To ensure the security and integrity of our Services. 
    
* _**Third party relationships.**_ To manage our vendor and partner relationships.
    
* _**Enforcement.**_ To enforce our [Terms of Use](https://matterport.com/terms-of-use) and other legal terms and policies.
    
* **Protection.** To protect our and others’ interests, rights, and property.
    
* _**Complying with law.**_ To comply with applicable legal requirements, such as tax and other government regulations and industry standards, contracts, and law enforcement requests.

Although the sections above describe our primary purpose in collecting your information, in many situations we have more than one purpose. For example, if you sign up for Services, we may collect your information to complete that transaction, but we also collect your information as we have a legitimate interest in maintaining your information after your transaction is complete so that we can quickly and easily respond to any questions about your Services. As a result, our collection and processing of your information is based in different contexts upon your consent, our need to perform a contract, our obligations under law, and/or our legitimate interest in conducting our business.

How we collect your information
-------------------------------

We obtain personal information from various sources. We do this in three main ways:

* _**When you give it to us.**_ You provide some of it directly such as by registering for an account. We also maintain your marketing preferences and the emails and other communications that you send us or otherwise contribute, such as customer support inquiries or posts to our customer message boards or forums. You might also provide us with information in other ways, including by responding to surveys, submitting a form or participating in contests or similar promotions. If you do not provide personal information when requested, you may not be able to use our Services if that information is necessary to provide you with the service or if we are legally required to collect it.
    
* _**When you use our Services.**_ We record some of your information automatically when you use our Services or Applications. We collect information about your activity on and interaction with the Services, such as your IP address(es), your device and browser type, the web page you visited before coming to our Website, what pages on our Website you visit and for how long and identifiers associated with your devices. If you’ve given us permission through your device settings, we may collect your location information in our applications. Some of this information is collected automatically using cookies and similar technologies when you use our Services or Applications, and some is collected automatically through your browser or from your device.
    
* _**From Third Parties.**_ We receive some of it from third parties like when you register for an account using a Third-Party Service. If you use a Third-Party Service to register for an account, the Third-Party Service may provide us with your Third-Party Service account information on your behalf, such as your name and email address (we don’t collect or store passwords you use to access Third Party Services). Your privacy settings on the Third-Party Service normally control what they share with us. Make sure you are comfortable with what they share by reviewing their privacy policies and, if necessary, modifying your privacy settings directly on the Third-Party Service.

Who we share your personal information with
-------------------------------------------

Matterport will not share, rent, sell or otherwise disclose any of the personal information that we collect about you to marketers or unaffiliated third parties. We share your personal information with trusted entities, as outlined below.

* _**Third-Party Service Providers.**_ We share personal information with certain of our third-party service providers, contractors, and processors, some of which may utilize artificial intelligence in their provision of services to Matterport, subject to contract terms that limit their use of personal information. We have service providers that provide services on our behalf in connection with the Services, such as website hosting, data analysis, marketing service, information technology and related infrastructure, customer service, email delivery, and auditing services. These service providers may need to access personal information to perform their services. We require these contractors to use or disclose this information only as necessary to perform services on our behalf in a manner consistent with this Privacy Policy, or as otherwise required by law.
    
* _**Third Party Plugins and Social Networks.**_ We may share personal information with website plugins, social media platforms or similar Third-Party Services to improve your experience, at your direction, or when you intentionally interact with the plug-in. For example, when you use a Third-Party Service to create or log in to your account, we may share your personal information with that Third Party Service.
    
* _**Business Partners and Resellers.**_ We share personal information with our business partners and value-added resellers or channel partners to facilitate sales in situations where Matterport does not directly sell our products and Services due to location, industry type or any other reason as determined solely by Matterport.
    
* _**Law enforcement or protecting rights and interests.**_ We disclose your personal information if we determine that such disclosure is reasonably necessary to comply with the law, protect our or others' rights, property, or interests (such as enforcing our [Terms of Use](https://matterport.com/terms-of-use)) or prevent fraud or abuse of Matterport or our Customers. We may disclose your personal information in response to lawful requests by public authorities, such as to meet national security or law enforcement requirements. We reserve the right to release information that we collect to law enforcement or other government officials, as we, in our sole and absolute discretion, deem necessary or appropriate.
    
* **Fraud Prevention.** We share personal information for the purposes of fraud protection, preventing fraud and minimizing associated risk for Matterport, its Partners and others using the Services.
    
* **Affiliates and Acquisitions.** If we’re involved in a reorganization, merger, acquisition, or sale of our assets, your data may be transferred as part of that deal. We share personal information with our corporate affiliates (e.g., parent company, sister companies, subsidiaries, joint ventures, or other companies under common control). If another company acquires, or plans to acquire, our company, business, or our assets, we will also share information with that company, including at the negotiation stage. We may also share personal information about you as part of a bankruptcy, corporate reorganization, merger, acquisition or other sale or transfer of Matterport’s assets or business. 
    
* **Other disclosures with your consent.** We may ask if you would like us to share your information with other unaffiliated third parties who are not described elsewhere in this Privacy Policy. 

Your choices and rights
-----------------------

You can make the following choices regarding your personal information:

* _**Access to your personal information.**_ You have the right to request access to your personal information. Additionally, under CPRA, VCDPA, and similar laws, you have the right to opt out of the sale of your personal information and to limit the use and disclosure of sensitive personal information. To exercise these rights please contact us at the address described below. If required by law, upon request, we will grant you reasonable access to the personal information that we have about you. We will provide this information in a portable format, if required. Note that California residents may be entitled to ask us for a notice describing what categories of personal information (if any) we share with third parties or affiliates for direct marketing.
    
* _**Changes to your personal information.**_ We rely on you to update and correct your personal information. Our Website allows you to modify or delete your account profile. If our Website does not permit you to update or correct certain information, please contact us as set forth in the [Contact us](https://matterport.com/privacy-policy#contact) section of this Privacy Policy in order to request that your information be modified. Note that we may keep historical information in our backup files as permitted by law.
    
* _**Deletion of your personal information.**_ As described in this Privacy Policy, we retain your personal information for the period necessary to provide the Services, unless a longer retention period is required or permitted by law. You may, however, request that we delete your personal information by contacting us at the address described below. If required by law we will grant a request to delete information, but you should note that in many situations we must keep your personal information to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, enforce our agreements, or for another one of our business purposes.
    
* _**Objection to certain processing.**_ You may object to our use or disclosure of your personal information by contacting us at the address described below.
    
* _**Online tracking.**_ We do not currently recognize automated browser signals regarding tracking mechanisms, which may include “Do Not Track” instructions.
    
* _**Promotional emails.**_ You may choose to provide us with your email address for the purpose of allowing us to send free newsletters, surveys, offers, and other promotional materials to you, as well as targeted offers from third parties. You can stop receiving promotional emails by following the unsubscribe instructions in e-mails that you receive. If you decide not to receive promotional emails, we may still send you service-related communications.
    
* _**Revocation of consent.**_ If you revoke your consent for the processing of personal information, then we may no longer be able to provide you services. In some cases, we may limit or deny your request to revoke consent if the law permits or requires us to do so, or if we are unable to adequately verify your identity. You may revoke consent to processing (where such processing is based upon consent) by contacting us at the address described below.

**Exercising your rights.** Please address written requests and questions about your rights to [\[email protected\]](https://matterport.com/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection). Depending on where you reside, we may ask you to prove your identity as required by certain jurisdictions laws. We may verify your identity by phone call or email, or, depending on the request, we will ask for information such as your name or other account information. We may also ask you to provide a signed declaration confirming your identity. Following a request, we will use reasonable efforts to supply, correct or delete personal information about you in our files.  We cannot respond to your request or provide you with personal information if we cannot verify your identity and confirm that the personal information relates to you.  In certain circumstances, we may decline a request to exercise the rights described above, particularly where we are unable to verify your identity or locate your information in our systems. If we are unable to comply with all or a portion of your request, we will provide a brief explanation.  

Please see the [Other jurisdictions](https://matterport.com/privacy-policy#other-jurisdictions) section below for additional information that may apply to you based on where you reside.

How we secure your personal information
---------------------------------------

While no service is completely secure, we have a security team dedicated to keeping personal information safe from alteration, disclosure and/or destruction. Matterport has adopted appropriate physical, electronic and managerial procedures to safeguard and secure the personal information we process. We follow generally accepted industry standards to protect the personal information submitted to us, both during transmission and once we receive it. Your account is protected by password for your privacy and security. We periodically review our information collection, storage and processing practices, including physical security measures, to guard against unauthorized access to systems.

Because the internet is not a completely secure environment, Matterport cannot warrant the security of any information a user transmits to Matterport or guarantee that information on the Services may not be accessed, disclosed, altered, and/or destroyed by breach of any of our physical, technical and/or managerial safeguards. You are responsible for maintaining the secrecy of your unique password and account information, and for controlling access to emails between a user and Matterport, at all times. You should limit access to your computer and/or mobile device and/or browser and sign off after you have finished accessing your account. We are not responsible for the functionality, privacy and/or security measures of any other organization and are not responsible for the practices employed by any websites and/or services linked to and/or from the Services, including the information and/or content contained therein.

How we retain your personal information
---------------------------------------

Generally, we will hold your personal information for as long as you are a customer and use Services to ensure accuracy and to help maintain quality of service or if we are obliged to retain such information for legal, regulatory, fraud prevention and legitimate business purposes.

The precise periods for which we keep your personal information vary depending on the nature of the information and why we need it. To determine the appropriate retention period for personal information, we consider the amount, nature, and sensitivity of the personal information, the potential risk of harm from unauthorized use and/or disclosure of your personal information, the purposes for which we process your personal information and whether we can achieve those purposes through other means, and the applicable legal requirements.

In some circumstances we may anonymize your personal information (so that it can no longer be associated with you) for research, statistical or other business purposes. We may use this aggregated, anonymized, or de-personalized information indefinitely without further notice.  We may retain personal information for a commercially reasonable time for backup, archival, audit purposes, and/or to comply with legal obligations, resolve disputes and enforce agreements. You can request further details of retention periods for different aspects of your personal information by contacting us.

International Data Transfers
----------------------------

We are a global business, with our primary location in the US. The personal information (or personal data) which we collect from you may be transferred to, and stored at, a destination outside the European Economic Area (“EEA”), including the US, Switzerland, India, and the Philippines. Where applicable law requires that a data transfer has a legal mechanism, we use the new Standard Contractual Clauses (SCCs) approved by the European Commission, Binding Corporate Rules (BCRs), or other legal methods available to us under applicable law. You acknowledge the transfer to, and storing, or processing outside of the EEA or UK of your personal data as set out in this Privacy Policy, and in the [Other jurisdictions](https://matterport.com/privacy-policy#other-jurisdictions) section below.

Other important information
---------------------------

**Links to third-party websites, apps or services.** This Privacy Policy only addresses the use and disclosure of personal information collected from you by Matterport. You should be aware that when you are using the Services, you may also use or be directed to other websites, applications or services of third parties that are beyond our control, and Matterport is not responsible for the privacy practices of third parties or the content of their websites, applications or services. We encourage you to read the posted privacy policy whenever interacting with any third-party website, application or service.

**Updates to this Notice.** We continuously monitor and update our practices to ensure compliance with evolving data protection laws, including the GDPR, CPRA, VCDPA, and other relevant regulations. We will from time to time update this Privacy Policy as we adopt new privacy practices and policies in response to updates in the law, to align with changing industry best-practices, and to reflect our product enhancements. We reserve the right to change this Privacy Policy at any time. Any changes to the Privacy Policy will be either posted on this page or communicated to you in writing by us, where we are legally required to do so. Changes to this Privacy Policy shall be applicable on the effective date set out in the updated Privacy Policy. The latest version of this Privacy Policy will be available to view on our Website.

**Children.** The Website and Services are not directed at children, and we do not knowingly collect personal information directly from users under the age of 13 or from other websites or services directed at children. Consistent with the Federal Children’s Online Privacy Protection Act of 1998 (“COPPA”), we will not knowingly request or collect personal information from any child under age 13 without obtaining the required parental consent.

**Conflict between this privacy notice and our Terms of Use or other terms.** Where there is a conflict between this Privacy Policy and an explicit provision of the [Terms of Use](https://matterport.com/terms-of-use), this Privacy Policy will prevail over those other Terms.

**Accessibility.** If you are visually impaired, you may access this notice through your browser’s audio reader.

**Information from other sources.** We may receive information about you, including personal information, from third parties, and may combine this information with other personal information we maintain about you. If we do so, this Privacy Policy governs any combined information that we maintain in a personally identifiable format.

**Collection and processing of sensitive information.** The Service do not collect, or process ‘sensitive information’ as defined by certain Data Privacy Laws, and our [Terms of Use](https://matterport.com/terms-of-use). As such, and in accordance with our [Terms of Use](https://matterport.com/terms-of-use), you shall not provide any such information as part of your user profile, as part of any correspondence, when you upload images, or by any other means with your use of the Service.

**Aggregated Information.** We may use information from images scanned and processed in an aggregated form for analytics and machine learning. The results of these activities do not contain or disclose any personal information that is identifiable to you. The Services are not designed or intended to collect personal information from your images, and you are responsible for any personal information depicted in the imagery. You should refrain from capturing any personal information if you object to the processing as described in this Privacy Policy. If personal information is captured in images that you have uploaded to Matterport Platform this information may be publicly displayed if you choose to display the underlying imagery publicly through the Service. If you do not wish to publicly display personal information depicted in the images you submit, you should either refrain from capturing such personal information in your images or designate the resulting 3D models as “private” in your Matterport Platform account. For additional information on designating your imagery as “public” or “private”, restricting third parties from editing or re-sharing your imagery, and the consequences of archiving your imagery, deleting your imagery and/or terminating your account, please also see the Platform Subscription Agreement. You are responsible for any personal information depicted in the imagery, and you should refrain from capturing any personal information if you object to the processing as described in this Privacy Policy.

**Automated decision-making and profiling.** Automated decision making refers to a decision that is taken solely on the basis of automated processing of your personal information, for example using software, artificial intelligence or other rating or scoring algorithms. Our use of AI includes enhancing user experiences, providing personalized services, and improving the accuracy of our digital twin creation through generative AI models trained on diverse datasets. In compliance with the EU AI Regulation, we ensure that our automated decision-making systems are transparent and explainable. We provide details about these automated services, instructions on how customers use, edit and turn-off these services, and customer support process for escalations. We offer mechanisms for our customers to turn off and/or edit these automated outputs to best suit their needs. Profiling uses automated processing which sometimes results in automated decision making, and in some cases does not.  When you sign up to use the Services, we may use certain personal information, for example your first name, last name, address and IP address to verify you are eligible to use the Services and to restrict your access if you are not, for example if you are resident in a country or region that is subject to a U.S. government embargo. We will also restrict access by use of automated decision-making and profiling to anyone on or, directly or indirectly, owned, in whole or part, by any person or persons on the U.S. Treasury Department’s List of Specially Designated Nationals and Blocked Persons or any other U.S. government list of parties with respect to transactions that are forbidden or restricted.

You have the right to not be subject to decision making which is solely based on automated processing and profiling, but only when that decision results in legal effects or otherwise significantly affects you. If you believe we have incorrectly made a decision based on automated decision-making and profiling, please contact us using the information in the [Contact us](https://matterport.com/privacy-policy#contact) section of this Privacy Policy. Your right not to be subject to automated decision making and profiling does not apply if the decision was necessary for entering into or performing a contract with you or is authorized by law and there are suitable safeguards for your rights and freedoms. However, in these situations, you can still obtain human intervention in the decision-making process and will make sure there are methods in place for you to express your point of view.

Other jurisdictions
-------------------

Personal information that you submit through the Services may be transferred to countries other than where you live. Your personal information may be transferred to countries that do not have the same data protection laws as the country in which you initially provided the information. The following provisions may apply to you depending on where you are located. If you chose to access services from somewhere other than your home country, you are responsible for compliance with local laws.

**Australia.** If you are an Australian resident, and you are dissatisfied with our handling of any complaint you raise under this Privacy Policy, you may wish to contact the [Office of the Australian Information Commissioner](https://www.oaic.gov.au/).

**Canada.** Personal information maintained and processed by our affiliates and third-party service providers in the U.S. and other foreign jurisdictions may be subject to disclosure pursuant to a lawful access request by U.S. or foreign courts or government authorities. We will not provide your information to third parties for marketing purposes without your prior consent. For more information about our privacy practices; to access, update or correct inaccuracies in your personal information; or if you have a question or complaint about the manner in which we or our service providers treat your personal information, please contact us as set forth in the [Contact us](https://matterport.com/privacy-policy#contact) section of this Privacy Policy.

**European Economic Area (EEA) and the United Kingdom (UK).** If you are located in the EEA, the UK we comply with applicable laws to provide an adequate level of data protection for the transfer of your personal data to the US. 

* **_Transfers outside the EEA and UK._** Where applicable law requires that a data transfer have legal mechanism, we use one or more of the following: Standard Contractual Clauses with a data recipient outside the EEA or the UK (or additionally, in the case of the UK, the International Data Transfer Agreement (IDTA) or Addendum to the Standard Contractual Clauses issued by the ICO), verification that the recipient has implemented Binding Corporate Rules, or other legal method available to us under applicable law.  
    
* _**Complaints.**_ If you are a resident of the EEA, and believe we process your information in scope of the General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR), you may direct your questions or complaints to the Office of the Data Protection Commissioner. If you are a resident of the UK, you may direct your questions or concerns to the UK Information Commissioner’s Office. To exercise your privacy rights set forth in this Privacy Policy, you may contact us as set forth in the [Contact us](https://matterport.com/privacy-policy#contact) section.

#### **United States** 

_**Connecticut.**_ The Connecticut Data Privacy Act (CTDPA) provides Connecticut residents with rights to access, correct, delete, and obtain a copy of their personal information, as well as the right to opt out of the processing of their personal data for purposes of targeted advertising, the sale of personal data, or profiling in furtherance of decisions that produce legal or similarly significant effects. To exercise these rights, you may contact us as set forth in the Contact us section.

_**Colorado.**_ The Colorado Privacy Act (CPA) provides Colorado residents with rights to access, correct, delete, and obtain a copy of their personal information, as well as the right to opt out of the processing of their personal data for purposes of targeted advertising, the sale of personal data, or profiling in furtherance of decisions that produce legal or similarly significant effects. To exercise these rights, you may contact us as set forth in the Contact us section.

_**Illinois.**_ The Illinois Biometric Information Privacy Act (BIPA), permits the collection, use, and storage of biometric information for the purpose of providing services. While we are committed to complying with BIPA’s requirements, including obtaining explicit consent before collecting biometric data and providing information about our data retention policies, we do not currently collect us or store biometric information as defined under BIPA. You may find more information in our statement on biometric identifiers located here. If you have any questions or concerns about our use of biometric data, you may contact us as set forth in the Contact us section.

_**Nevada.**_ This notice is provided to you pursuant to Nevada state law. Nevada state privacy laws permit us to make marketing calls to existing customers, but if you prefer not to receive marketing calls, you may be placed on our internal opt-out list by contacting us as set forth in the Contact us section. Or you may also contact the Nevada Bureau of Consumer Protection, Office of the Nevada Attorney General, 555 E. Washington St., Ste 3900, Las Vegas, NV 89101; telephone 702-486-3132; email: [\[email protected\]](https://matterport.com/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection).

_**Texas.**_ If you have a complaint, first contact us as set forth in the Contact us section. If you still have an unresolved complaint regarding the company’s money transmission or currency exchange activity, please direct your complaint to the Texas Department of Banking: 2601 North Lamar Boulevard, Austin, TX 78705-4294; 1-877-276-5554 (toll free); [www.dob.texas.gov](http://www.dob.texas.gov/).

_**Vermont.**_ In accordance with Vermont law, we will not share information we collect about you with companies outside of Matterport except as required or permitted by law. For example, we may share information to service your accounts, complete requested transactions, or to provide rewards or benefits to which you are entitled.

_**Virginia.**_ Under the Virginia Consumer Data Protection Act (VCDPA), Virginia residents have the right to access, correct, delete, and obtain a copy of their personal information, as well as the right to opt out of the processing of their personal data for purposes of targeted advertising, the sale of personal data, or profiling in furtherance of decisions that produce legal or similarly significant effects. To exercise these rights, you may contact us as set forth in the Contact us section.**_California – California Consumer Privacy Act (“CCPA”) and California Privacy Rights Act (“CPRA”)._**  This Section applies solely to all visitors, users, and others who reside in the State of California, and only applies to personal information for which Matterport is a “Business” (as defined in the CCPA). This does not apply to personal information we collect from you during our provision of Services to you where you are an employee, owner, director, officer or contractor of a company, partnership, sole proprietorship, non-profit or government agency. It applies to personal information we collect from California Residents on or through our Services and through other means (such as information collected offline or in person). Any terms defined in the CCPA/CPRA have the same meaning when used in this notice.

* _**Important Note.**_ We do not “sell” personal information as most people would typically understand that term. However, we do allow certain third-party partners and providers to collect information about consumers directly through our Services for purposes of analyzing and optimizing our Services and advertisements (ads), providing content and ads that are more relevant, measuring statistics and the success of ad campaigns, and detecting and reporting fraud. To the extent this practice is interpreted to constitute a “sale” under the CCPA, please see our Cookies Policy for more information including how to exercise your rights to opt-out of cookies, analytics and personalized advertising.
    
* _**Rights and choices for California Residents.**_ In addition to those privacy rights described in “Your choices”, if you reside in the state of California, you have the following additional privacy rights:
    
    * _Personal information sales rights._ You have the right to direct us not to sell your personal information. 
        
    * _Non-discrimination right._ You have the right not to be discriminated against when you exercise any of the rights under the CCPA. Unless permitted by the CCPA, we will not deny you goods or Services or actually charge, or suggest we charge you different prices or rates, or provide different levels of quality for goods and Services.
        
* _**Exercising your rights.**_ To exercise your rights please submit your request to [\[email protected\]](https://matterport.com/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection). As mandated by CCPA, we will acknowledge receipt of your request within 10 days and will respond within 45 days of receipt of your request, but if we require more time (up to an additional 45 days) we will let you know. In some cases, you may designate an authorized agent to submit requests to exercise certain privacy rights on your behalf.  We will require verification that you provided the authorized agent permission to make a request on your behalf. You must provide us with a copy of the signed permission you have given to the authorized agent to submit the request on your behalf and verify your own identity directly with us. If you are an authorized agent submitting a request on behalf of an individual, you must attach a copy of: (a) A completed written notice indicating that you have authorization to act on the consumer’s behalf signed by you and the consumer; and (b) if you are a business, proof that you are registered with the appropriate Secretary of State to conduct business in California. If we do not receive both pieces of information, the request will be denied.
    
* _**Right to Know Disclosures.**_ During the past 12 months we have collected the following categories of information about California residents. This includes information about visitors, end users, workers, vendors, suppliers and any other person interacting with us either online or offline. Not all information is collected about all individuals. For instance, we may collect different information from applicants for employment than from customers. 

| **Category** | **Examples** | **Collected?** |
| --- | --- | --- |
| Category A: Identifiers | First and last name, email address, IP address, or similar identifiers. | Yes |
| Category B: Personal information categories listed in the California Customer Records statute (Cal. Civ. Code § 1798.80(e)) | A name, signature, Social Security number, physical characteristics or description, address, telephone number, passport number, driver’s license or state identification card number, insurance policy number, education, employment, employment history, bank account number, credit card number, debit card number, or any other financial information, medical information, or health insurance information. Some personal information included in this category may overlap with other categories. | Yes |
| Category C: Protected classification characteristics under California or federal law | Age (40 years or older), race, color, ancestry, national origin, citizenship, religion or creed, marital status, medical condition, physical or mental disability, sex (including gender, gender identity, gender expression, pregnancy or childbirth and related medical conditions), sexual orientation, veteran or military status, genetic information (including familial genetic information). | No  |
| Category D: Commercial information | Records of personal property, products or services purchased, obtained, or considered, or other purchasing or consuming histories or tendencies. | Yes |
| Category E: Biometric information | Genetic, physiological, behavioral, and biological characteristics, or activity patterns used to extract a template or other identifier or identifying information, such as fingerprints, faceprints, and voiceprints, iris or retina scans, keystroke, gait, or other physical patterns, and sleep, health, or exercise data. | No  |
| Category F: Internet or other similar network activity | Browsing history, search history, information on a consumer's interaction with a website, application, or advertisement. | Yes |
| Category G: Geolocation data | Physical location or movements. | Yes |
| Category H: Sensory data | Audio, electronic, visual, thermal, olfactory, or similar information. | Yes |
| Category I: Professional or employment-related information | Current or past job history or performance evaluations. | No  |
| Category J: Non-public education information (per the Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act (20 U.S.C. Section 1232g, 34 C.F.R. Part 99) | Education records directly related to a student maintained by an educational institution or party acting on its behalf, such as grades, transcripts, class lists, student schedules, student identification codes, student financial information, or student disciplinary records. | No  |
| Category: K. Inferences drawn from other personal information | Profile reflecting a person's preferences, characteristics, psychological trends, predispositions, behavior, attitudes, intelligence, abilities, and aptitudes. | Yes |

Contact us
----------

If you have any questions or comments about this Privacy Policy, you may contact us by email at [\[email protected\]](https://matterport.com/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection) or by mail at:

Matterport, Inc. 352 E. Java Dr. Sunnyvale, CA 94089 USA

Alternatively, you may contact our customer support team using our toll-free number at +1 (833) 408-0104 or submit a request via our customer support portal at: [https://support.matterport.com/hc/en-us/requests/new](https://support.matterport.com/hc/en-us/requests/new).

**EU Residents.** If you are located in the European Union, pursuant to Article 27 of the General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR), Matterport has appointed European Data Protection Office (EDPO) as its GDPR representative. You can contact EDPO regarding matters pertaining to the GDPR by:

* Using EDPO’s online request form: [https://edpo.com/gdpr-data-request/](https://edpo.com/gdpr-data-request/%C2%A0) 
    
* Writing to EDPO at Avenue Huart Hamoir 71, 1030 Brussels, Belgium

**UK Residents.** If you are located in the United Kingdom, Pursuant to Article 27 of the UK GDPR, Matterport has appointed EDPO UK Ltd as its UK GDPR representative in the UK. You can contact EDPO UK regarding matters pertaining to the UK GDPR:

* Using EDPO’s online request form: [https://edpo.com/uk-gdpr-data-request/](https://edpo.com/uk-gdpr-data-request/)
    
* Writing to EDPO UK at 8 Northumberland Avenue, London WC2N 5BY, United Kingdom

**AI Privacy Notice**
---------------------

Last updated: November 15, 2024

### **How Matterport Uses AI and Generative AI**

At Matterport, we are committed to developing innovative AI experiences to enhance our services and products. Our proprietary Matterport AI is core to our platform and the creation of the Matterport Spaces or 3D Digital Twins. The Matterport AI has learned from, and continues to learn from tens of millions of spaces, enabling Matterport to provide the most realistic and valuable Matterport Spaces. Importantly, our AI systems are designed to process spatial and environmental data, not personal data, unless explicitly uploaded by users. In compliance with the EU AI Regulation, we conduct assessments to ensure that our AI systems meet safety, transparency, and fairness requirements. We are implementing risk management systems, data governance measures, and continuous monitoring to mitigate any risks associated with our AI systems. Our customers can trust that our AI constantly improves with every space uploaded to our platform.

### **Generative AI at Matterport**

Our additional collection of generative AI features, including features of property intelligence, such automated measurements, descriptions, automated de-furnishing, are designed to further help businesses and individuals solve complex spatial problems, boost creativity, and streamline operations. Our goal is to leverage AI to create new and exciting possibilities for our users. In line with the EU AI Regulation, we ensure that our generative AI models are transparent, explainable, and accountable. We provide users with clear information about how our AI systems work, their intended purpose, and the data used for training these models, which primarily involves non-personal spatial and environmental data.

### **How Generative AI Works in Digital Twin Creatio**n

Generative AI models are sophisticated algorithms trained on a variety of data, including spatial, visual, and geometric information. These models learn to recognize patterns and relationships within the data, enabling them to create highly accurate and detailed Digital Twins. For instance:

* 3D Space Generation: Matterport’s AI models are trained on extensive datasets of 3D spaces, allowing them to generate coherent and realistic digital representations of physical environments. These models can accurately replicate the dimensions, layouts, and features of real-world spaces, enabling users to explore and interact with digital replicas of their environments.
    
* Image and Object Recognition: Matterport’s AI models learn from billions of images and their spatial relationships, enabling them to identify and accurately recreate objects and features within a space. By analyzing the visual data, Matterport’s AI can capture and process detailed 3D models that reflect the precise appearance and structure of a physical environment.

Generative AI in Digital Twin creation enhances the accuracy and realism of the digital representations, providing users with a powerful tool to visualize, analyze, and interact with their physical spaces in a digital format.

### **Data Sources and Training**

To train Matterport’s AI models effectively for Digital Twin creation, we utilize a combination of publicly available data, licensed information, and data shared on our platform. We ensure that data used for training is anonymized and predominantly non-personal, particularly when it involves personal information. In compliance with the EU AI Regulation, we implement robust data governance measures to ensure the quality and integrity of the data used in our AI systems. This includes procedures for data anonymization, minimization, and regular audits to verify compliance. This practice helps us maintain the privacy and security of our users' data while continually improving our AI capabilities.

By using a diverse range of data sources, our AI models can learn to accurately replicate real-world environments, creating highly detailed and realistic Digital Twins. The anonymization process ensures that no personal or identifiable information is included in the training data, safeguarding user privacy and security. This approach allows us to enhance our AI's performance continually while adhering to strict data protection standards.

### **Privacy and Data Protection**

We prioritize the privacy and security of our users' data. Our robust internal Privacy Program ensures responsible data usage across all our products, including generative AI. We adhere to key principles such as privacy and security, fairness and inclusion, robustness and safety, transparency and control, and governance and accountability. Matterport's AI systems are designed to process spatial and environmental data rather than personal data unless explicitly uploaded by users.

### **Commitment to Responsible AI**

Our commitment to responsible AI development is driven by a cross-disciplinary team dedicated to ensuring that our AI technologies benefit people and society. By investing in responsible AI practices, we strive to provide equitable access to information and opportunities while protecting user privacy. In accordance with the EU AI Regulation, we adhere to principles of safety, transparency, accountability, non-discrimination, and fairness in all our AI initiatives. We conduct impact assessments, engage with stakeholders, and ensure that our AI systems are designed and deployed in a manner that respects fundamental rights and values.

### **Transparency and User Rights**

We believe in transparency regarding how we use data for AI training. Users have rights related to their data, and we ensure compliance with relevant data protection regulations. Our data handling practices include anonymization, secure processing, and strict access controls to safeguard personal information. Matterport’s AI systems do not process personal data unless explicitly uploaded by users, ensuring that our data processing activities are transparent and user-focused.

### **Future of AI at Matterport**

We are excited about the future possibilities of generative AI and are committed to continuously enhancing our AI technologies. By drawing from industry best practices, we ensure that our AI remains cutting-edge, secure, and beneficial for our users. As part of our commitment to compliance with the EU AI Regulation, we will continue to innovate responsibly and ensure that our AI systems meet evolving regulatory standards. We look forward to exploring new ways AI can transform everyday experiences and drive innovation while maintaining the highest standards of safety, transparency, and accountability.
